Kartiki Sahu

Lead Software Engineer

Solution-driven professional excelling in the highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. I have **7 years** of experience in developing pixel-perfect UI using JavaScript, NodeJs, Angular, Polymer, Twitter Bootstrap, HTML, SCSS, & jQuery

+91 9	860514359	/ 72767	69618
כוכי ן	000314333	1 12101	03010

kartikis26@gmail.com

github.com/kartiki-sahu

in linkedin.com/in/kartikisahu

Skills

Language:JavaScript, Node.js, PythonFramework:Angular, Polymer, React, DjangoDatabase:MongoDBCloud:Cloudfoundary and GE's Predix

Others: HTML, CSS, Twitter Bootstrap, Iguery

Work Experience (7 years)

Lead Software Engineer | Globallogic India Pvt. Ltd | July 2019 - Present

Consulted to several fortune 500 customers in a span of 2 years. A high-level summary below

VMWare: July 2020 - Present

- Building a solution to facilitate sales team endorse their products. Designing and Developing pixel-perfect, reusable web-components.
- Added Server-side Pagination, caching and O-Auth
- Leading a team of 2+ Associates
- Extremely passionate about learning new technologies. Self-educated myself on fundamentals of Docker
- Experience in hiring, mentoring and managing top talent
- Worked closely with business teams, product owners, quality leads, senior managers throughout the product lifecycle
- Using Angular 11, Node Js, typescript, Clarity, HTML and SCSS

T-Mobile: Dec 2019 - Jun 2020

- Build Solution to automate QA's Regression, Progression & Sanity test cases. Empowered them to schedule these test cases and displayed intutive reports covering failure reason, snapshots and video
- Designed and Developed a dynamic theme-based dashboard and it's architecture. Developed pixel-perfect, reusable web-components
- Lead a team of 3+ Associates
- Wrote unit test cases and quality controlled using Sonarqube
- Experience in hiring, mentoring and managing top talent
- Worked closely with business teams, product owners, quality leads, senior managers throughout the product lifecycle
- Used Angular 9, Node JS, SCSS, Twitter Bootstrap, HTML and SCSS
- Lead team of 3+ associates

AT&T: July 2019 - Dec 2019

- Build Solution to manage the smart device. Designed dashboard capturing near-real-time IoT data facilitating admin to monitor device health
- Planned and engineered RESTful web services in NodeJS and Python
- Extremely passionate about learning new technologies. Self-educated myself on fundamentals of Python
- Handled end to end workflow for UI project
- Worked with project managers to design and implement scalable solutions.
- Used Angular 8, Python, Node JS, Twitter Bootstrap, HTML and SCSS

Senior Software Engineer | InfoCepts Technologies | Mar 2016 - May 2019

General Electrics: Mar 2016 - May 2019

- Built cutting edge IoT solutions for Current division of GE. Designed and developed consumer-facing UI applications.
- Created re-usable UI web-components. Here is a video demonstrating entire work
- Results-oriented, ability to handle multiple competing priorities in a fast-paced environment
- · Developed Node parsers to process high volume, complex and dynamically structured CSV files and store the data into
- NoSQL database
- Designed API contract in Node Js, implemented caching and server-side pagination in Polymer
- Deployed application on PaaS platforms like Cloud Foundry and Predix
- Lead a team of 2+ Associates
- Extremely passionate about learning new technologies. Self-educated myself on fundamentals of Polymer
- Worked with project managers to design and implement scalable solutions
- Experience in hiring, mentoring and managing top talent
- Used Polymer, Node Js, HTML and CSS

Software Engineer | Crowdera | Jun 2014 - Jan 2016

- Build an intuitive, responsive, user-friendly Crowdfunding website to enable fundraiser to fund dispatcher come together at one place one platform.
- Implemented 2 payment gateway FirstGiving and PayPal. Added authentication and security using Google O-Auth and Gmail API
- Designed and developed in-house URL shortener saving the company licensing cost of an external tool
- Determined operational feasibility by analyzing problem definition, requirements and proposed solution
- Worked with project managers to design and implement scalable solutions
- Drove operational improvements which resulted in savings and improved profit margins
- Extremely passionate about learning new technologies. Self-educated myself on fundamentals of Groovy on Grails
- Used Groovy, Grails, GSP, Twitter Bootstrap, HTML and CSS

Education

Bachelor of Engineering Specilization in Information Technology | Jun 2010 - May 2014

Karamveer Dadasaheb Kannamwar College of Engineering, Nagpur University

Volunteering Experience

Coding Bootcamp instructor | InfoCepts | 2018 - 2019

- HTML & CSS for beginners
- JavaScript for beginners

CSR Activities | InfoCepts | 2016 - 2019

- Mentor and Guardian of Chinteshwar School
- Child Development activity in BGS Girls High School, Hope Child Development Centre Chankapur, Dayaram
- Wade High School
- Tree Plantation
- Diwali distribute happiness

Certified Listener | 7 Cups | 2020 - Present

Being a certified listener I listen to individual's grievance and try to console them

Honour and Awards

- Spot Award | GlobalLogic | Aug 2019
- Project Transform Award | InfoCepts | Aug 2019
 - A most innovative project award
- Synergy Team Award | InfoCepts Technologies | 2017 2019
 - Awarded thrice for being consistent and marking success stories back to back
- Star Award | InfoCepts Technologies | 2017 2019
 - Awarded twice for being instrumental and most helpful member in the team